# **Matthew Cullen**

Penfield, New York, 14526 | 585-831-0531 | m23.cullen@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Software Engineer with team leadership experience, an eye for detail and passion for creating beautiful responsive web pages. Loves learning, quick to understand and apply new concepts, collaborative and highly creative. Works well under pressure and adapts to change easily. Community oriented. Currently loving learning Korean and C++

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails | JavaScript | React | Redux | Typescript | HTML5/CSS | Git | MongoDB | Linux | Node | Express

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School 09/ 2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Software Engineering Remote Learning Program Course Report's Bootcamps: Ranked #1 for 2019-2020

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Kpop Merchandise Exchange Github | Hosted with Firebase**

08/2020

I want to give international fans of Korean music a better way to exchange merchandise

## **Technology Used**

- JavaScript/React/Redux to manage, manipulate and display data
- Semantic-UI-React components + HTML5/CSS for UI/UX
- Google Firebase to deploy, save time, implement login/auth, NoSql database and file storage
- I used React components from my Chat App to quickly set up 1:1 chat features

### Chat App Github | Hosted with Firebase

05/2020

A way for people to chat in private or public user created channels

I was challenged to design the UI and the NoSql database structure

#### **Technology Used**

- Google Firebase Realtime Database made it easy to structure my data in Json
  It also provided functions to listen to changes being made to the NoSql collections.
- To save time I chose to use React/Redux with HTML5/CSS/Semantic-UI as my frontend

# Pet Assistant Frontend Backend | Demo

03/2020

This was my first time using a React/Redux and I wanted to help people who care for animals I created a way to keep track of important information about your pets simply and quickly

# **Technology Used**

- JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS (frontend)
- Ruby/Rails, Sqlite3 (backend)

# Online Library Github | Demo

02/2020

A way for book lovers to keep track of their collections

I was challenged to use an Object Oriented Programming approach and implement Google OAuth Also created my own login/authentication for users without a Google account.

#### **Technology Used**

- JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap (frontend)
- Ruby/Rails, PostgreSQL (backend)

# **LIVE WEBSITES + CODING TUTORIALS**

Coding Tutorials | Chat App | Twice Fansite

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Data Entry, Answer Net. Remote work

Three month contract

Assist NYS unemployment office with claim submissions

Baker, Wegmans. Rochester New York

07/2017 - 02/2019

Pay close attention to recipe details and quality of product

Quality assurance/supervisor, Harbec. Ontario New York

06/2011 - 02/2016

• Led and managed a team of quality inspectors